Villains aren't born. They're made.
Kraven the Hunter is a action, adventure,
thriller film directed by J.C. Chandor.
Kraven Kravinoff's complex relationship with his ruthless gangster father, Nikolai, starts him down a path of vengeance with brutal
consequences, motivating him to become not only the greatest hunter in the world, but also one of its most feared.
Sergei Kravinoff / Kraven the Hunter, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson.
Calypso Ezili, played by Ariana DeBose.
Dmitri Kravinoff, played by Fred Hechinger.
Aleksei Sytsevich, played by Alessandro Nivola.
The Foreigner, played by Christopher Abbott.
Nikolai Kravinoff, played by Russell Crowe.
Kraven the Hunter is a 2024 American superhero film
featuring the character from Marvel Comics.
It is the sixth film in Sony's Spider-Man Universe (SSU).
Aaron Taylor-Johnson stars as Kraven, alongside Ariana DeBose, Fred
Hechinger, Alessandro Nivola, Christopher Abbott, and Russell Crowe.
Directed by J.C.
Chandor and written by Richard Wenk, Art Marcum and Matt Holloway, the film explores Kraven's
relationship with his father and his path to becoming the greatest hunter.
Kraven was considered for film appearances several times before Sony Pictures became interested in a
standalone film for the character, as part of its new shared universe, in mid-2017.
Wenk was hired in August 2018, and Chandor entered negotiations to direct in August
2020, and was confirmed in May 2021 when Taylor-Johnson was cast.
Filming took place from late March until mid-June
in London, Iceland, and Glasgow.
Following two years of delays, Kraven the Hunter was released in the United
States on December 13, 2024, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film was a box-office failure, grossing $62 million worldwide against a
$110–130 million budget, and received negative reviews from critics.
Following its release, Sony halted development on further SSU films.
The film explores themes of hunter, superhero,
villain, based on comic, supervillain.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.